ALEKSA TEŠIĆ

P Belgrade, Serbia ☑ aleksatesicteske@gmail.com ☐ (+381) 60 424 37 69 ☐ github.com/Imafikus

ABOUT

Software engineer experienced in building and maintaining everything from CI/CD pipelines and deployments to application frontends. Always programming something. Currently mostly interested in software architecture and design. Record collector and Warhammer enthusiast. Big fan of stoner rock and a guitar player.

SKILLS

ACTIVELY USING / USED	HAD SOME EXPERIENCE	COLLABORATION
Go TS / JS Python, Flask, Selenium React + Tailwind	R C C++ Java	Git Jira and other similar tools Confluence and other similar tools
Node + Express Terraform, GCP Bash, Github Actions Postgres, MongoDB Ansible, Vagrant Docker, Jenkins K8s, Helm	Pascal Haskell Angular	

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Microsoft (April 2024 - present)

Part of the CIQ team in Microsoft responsible for smart suggestion and writing assistance features in various Microsoft products. Some of them include Outlook, Word and Teams.

Main technologies used: Typescript, Azure, React

Microsoft Development Center Serbia

SRE (until October 2022) & Software Engineer - Tenderly (March 2022 - November 2023)

Responsible for the internal tooling and CI / CD setup of the company.

Designed and extended custom config system used in the whole backend codebase.

Maintained and extended in-house developed CLI.

Maintained and extended CI / CD pipeline, ensuring that code quality checks are in place and extended the CD part in order to adjust to growing number of engineers and environments.

Also worked on creating multiple microservices whose purpose was to catch regressions we had on our data pipeline.

Main technologies used: Go, K8s, GCP, Bash

tenderly.co

Notify Me - Co-Founder (October 2018 - present)

Notify Me aims to change the way people track sites by providing them with meaningful changes and not just simple diffs.

Developed the first version of the site completely on my own. Currently working in a team of 3. I'm currently wearing multiple hats, from engineering to customer relation and marketing.

Main technologies used: Python, Flask, Selenium, Terrafom, GCP, React, Tailwind

notify-me.rs

Devops Engineer - Connect the Dots (September 2021 - March 2022)

Worked on migration from docker based setup to GKE. Integrated tracing accross all microservices in order to pinpoint performance pain points. Implemented new and improved existing CI / CD Github Actions pipelines. Deployed and improved existing IaC setup via Terraform.

 $Main\ technologies\ used:\ Terrafom,\ K8s,\ GCP,\ Github\ Actions,\ Typescript,\ Python$

ctd.ai

Associate and Board Member at Petnica Science Center (September 2017 - present)

Attended CS course for 3 years and then stayed there as a junior assistant on both CS and TEH departments. Organized and held lectures from various CS fields and helped attendees with their summer projects.

I'm currently working as head of TEH department and as a technical associate on CS department. Current work consists of planning yearly course cycles and managing a team of ~10 junior assistants and organizing guest lectures from people relevant to the STEM field.

From September of 2023. I'm also a board member of Petnica Science Center and I'm directly involved in day-to-day operations and future planning for the PSC.

Junior Devops Engineer - Itekako (September 2020 - June 2021)

Worked on various services for different customers. Most of the work was done on bare metal machines which were fully set up via Ansible while local development used Vagrant.

 $Most \ notable \ project \ I \ worked \ on \ included \ completely \ automating \ deployment \ workflow \ for \ Node. js \ based \ app \ written \ for \ Atlas Copco$

Apart from that, various smaller tasks were done via mostly bash and / or Python scripts. Part of the job also included technical support for the development team of Itekako.

Main technologies used: Ansible, Vagrant, Bash, Python, Docker, Jenkins

Junior Backend Engineer - Penta Fintech (March 2019 - August 2020)

Started in Cards team whose main task was ensuring smooth communication with our banking provider - SolarisBank. Core responsibilites were implementation of business logic and integrations with various smaller providers.

Apart from that, major part of the job was refactoring old ES5 Javascript code into ES6 Typescript while, at the same time, breaking down monolith based code into smaller services and improving test coverage.

In the last few months of my employment at Penta I was transferred to the BackOffice team whose main task was ensuring that our internal CRM app worked properly.

Main technologies used: Node + Express, Postgres, Typescript

Upwork / Freelancing (December 2017 - March 2019)

Mostly worked on smaller python based projects with some HTML here and there. Stopped when I joined Penta, since working 2 jobs and going to faculty just wasn't possible.

Main technologies used: Python, HTML

EDUCATION

University of Belgrade, Faculty of Mathematics (2017 - 2021)

Department of Computer Science - Informatics BSc